Paweł **ADAMCZAK Backend Developer**

• https://pawelad.me



+48 732 005 766

Kraków, Poland



I'm a backend developer with almost 10 years of professional experience. I enjoy using and creating software that can be called objectively good, or as close to it as possible. I like tasks that are out of my comfort zone and the knowledge that comes with them. I believe that good practices and attention to detail are very important in general, and especially crucial in IT. I think humility and open-mindedness are two of the most important qualities a person can have.

Skills

Programming Languages Python, Go

Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Elasticsearch, Redshift, DynamoDB Django, Django REST Framework, Flask, FastAPI, Celery, pytest Frameworks Libraries mypy, Pydantic, httpx, Click, black, Ruff, Nox, tox, pip-tools, MkDocs Docker, Docker Compose, Terraform, CloudFormation, Ansible Tools

Other AWS, nginx, dokku, OpenAPI, JSON Schema, Sentry, Bootstrap, GraphQL



EXPERIENCE

Present November 2024

Python Developer, NARVI

Remote / Helsinki, Finland

- Part of the main product backend team that's responsible for maintaining the current codebase and adding new features.
- Implemented new automated anti money laundering checks (e.g. based on user IP address).

Python PostgreSQL Django Django REST Framework Celery Ansible

November 2024 August 2018

Backend Engineer, TWENTY3

Remote / Milton Keynes, UK

- > Integral part of the team that rewrote company's main football data ingestion pipeline, that imports and post-processes thousands of football events every day (from multiple data providers), and exposes them through an internal API.
- Responsible for productising proof of concepts created by the Data Science team into MVPs.
- ➤ Helped with implementing best practices, such as:
 - > Developing continuous integration and continuous delivery pipelines
 - > Creating Docker based development and production environments
 - > Using JSON Schema to create dynamic and data driven APIs
 - > Maintaining a CloudFormation based IaaC stack
 - > Adding Python type hints
 - > Using Pydantic for validating data from all our data providers
 - > Using Sentry for error and performance tracking
 - Centralizing log digestion
- > Helped create tools used by major football clubs, media and betting companies, including SkySports, Squawka, LiveScore and William Hill.

Python PostgreSQL Redis Django Django REST Framework Celery Pydantic AWS RDS ECS Fargate CloudFormation | Circle CI | Sentry | Go | GraphQL

July 2018 September 2017

Platform Developer, VM FARMS

Toronto, Canada

- Part of a platform engineering team that maintained:
 - > Custom-built deployment pipeline for our clients
 - > Client facing portal, that was used to configure app environments and trigger new deployments
 - > All-purpose internal CLI for our operations team, that was the glue between Terraform, Ansible, Consul and Vault
- Worked directly with our in-house operations team to provide them with the tools to efficiently provision, configure and continuously support our client's infrastructure.

Python PostgreSQL MySQL Django Click Terraform Ansible Consul Vault Vagrant AWS

August 2017 October 2016

Backend Developer, OMNI DIGITAL

Bristol, UK

- ▶ Helped create and maintain internal and public facing projects for clients such as NHS, UK Chamber of Shipping and SWNS.
- Implemented a company-wide Ansible stack used for all deployments.

Python MySQL Elasticsearch Django Wagtail Ansible Digital Ocean

September 2016 September 2015

Python Developer, SIDNET SOLUTIONS

Remote / Warsaw, Poland

- Created and maintained:
 - > Schedoodle, an internal tool that helped track work availability of all remote employees
 - Official Polish site for Kolbe personality tests
 - Canola trading platform made for one of the biggest Polish oil distributors
- Responsible for releasing and maintaining some of our open source projects on GitHub.

Python PostgreSQL Django Bootstrap Digital Ocean

September 2015 April 2015

Backend Developer, JMR TECHNOLOGIES

Warsaw, Poland

- Helped develop and release two of the company's biggest (at the time) Python projects:
 - > Fully multilingual and customisable product knowledge base
 - Parcel tracking status aggregator that integrated with multiple delivery companies
- Responsible for managing our production server and creating most of our provisioning automation scripts.

Python MySQL Elasticsearch Django Fabric



EDUCATION

Warsaw University of Technology 2013 - 2016

2010 - 2013 I Liceum Ogólnokształcące w Zielonej Górze



PROJECTS

PYMONZO

github.com/pawelad/pymonzo https://pymonzo.pawelad.dev/

Modern Python API client for Monzo public API.

Fully type annotated, with explicitly defined and validated API schemas (via Pydantic), sensible defaults, easy authentication (with automatic access token refreshing) and optional Rich support for pretty printing.

Python Pydantic httpx GitHub CI MkDocs Read the Docs

MONZ

Simple CLI for quickly accessing your Monzo account.

Built on top of pymonzo.

Python Click Rich GitHub CI MkDocs Read the Docs

FAKESTER

Rickroll your boss friend while preserving the element of surprise.

Simple Django website that allows creating URL redirects that help fool your boss friend.

Python Django Bootstrap GitHub CI dokku

A LANGUAGES

INTERESTS

English









Polish

- traveling
- nba
- live music
- open source
- photography
- music making
- tv series
- movies

66 REFERENCES

Michał Wojciechowski CEO, SIDNET SOLUTIONS michal@sidnet.info

Alexandre Byeon

Principal SRE, PRODIGY EDUCATION alexandre@byeon.ca

Kyle Joseph

Full Stack Developer, TWENTY3 kyle@seoplay.co.uk